A Guide to the Virginia State Commission on Conservation and Development, Minutes and Program Meeting Books, 1926-1933
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia State Commission on Conservation and Development, Minutes and Program Meeting Books, 1926-1933
Library of Virginia
23645
10 volumes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the State Commission on Converservation and Development, 30 January 1951.
Biographical/Historical Information
The State Commission on Conservation and Development was established by the 1926 General Assembly. Throughout the years the Commission experienced many changes in its' function and responsibilities. The following is a chronology documenting the various changes in names for this agency: (1) State Commission on Conservation and Development, 1926-1938; (2) Virginia Conservation Commission, 1938-1948; (3) Department of Conservation and Economic Development, 1948-1985; (4) Department of Conservation and Historic Resources, 1985-1989; and (5) Department of Conservation and Recreation, 1989-.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains ten volumes that provide minutes and program meetings for the first five years of the State Commission on Conservation and Development. The minute volumes are carbon copies that usually provide the date of the meeting, time, location of meeting, list of commissioners in attendance, other participants, meeting agenda and business accomplished.
The program meeting books provide in outline format a list of actions taken on minutes from the previous month. Some program volumes may contain carbon copies of staff meeting minutes. Most of the volumes contain monthly reports for the following divisions: Geological Survey, Virginia Forest Service, Water Resources and Power, History and Archaeology and Secretarial and Advertising. The monthly division reports may include financial statements, correspondence and statistical report of activities and accomplishments of the respective divisions. One volume of special meeting minutes of the Commission, dated October of 1932, discusses the dismissal of Chapin Jones from the position of State Forester as requested by William E. Carson, Chairman of the State Commission on Conservation and Development. Some volumes contain financial information on the development of Shenandoah National Park project.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Minutes, 1926 July 16 - 1927 December 31 (Box 1)
- Program meeting book, 1926 October 15 - 1927 December 16 (Box 2)
- Minutes, 1928 January 20 - November 16 (Box 3)
- Program meeting book, 1927 July 9 - 1928 December 21 (Box 4)
- Minutes, 1929 February 15 - 1930 June 20 (Box 5)
- Program meeting book, 1929 February 15 - 1930 June 20 (Box 6)
- Minutes, 1930 July 25 - 1931 May 8 (Box 7)
- Program meeting book, 1930 July 25 - 1931 June 19 (Box 8)
- Minutes and special meetings, 1931 July 14 - 1933 August 14 (Box 9)
- Program meeting book, 1931 July 14 - 1933 June 9 (Box 10)